But we are a week from November
and whether you're doing this throughout
your workplace or at home with a
loved one on federal assistance,
open enrollment time for
Healthcare is here. We're doing,
we're doing it right now. License
insurance agent Kelly,
pardon of health markets insurance
is available to help you through
the red tape and the techno speak.
So good morning to you, Kelly.
So good morning.
Let's talk about open enrollment.
When is it and is this a
pretty complicated situation
for folks, it can be
for some people.
Open enrollment starts November 1st
and it runs through January 15th.
So this is the time for people who have
individual plans to find a new plan,
change a plan and run at it.
So these are for folks who get
insurance through like the government
through the Affordable Healthcare Act.
This is individual plans and also
there's a little wrinkle that added
was added this year for the better.
People that are on group plans
where employers are not paying for
spouses and children can now go
get a subsidized plan for just.
Them. So there's some good
things that happened this
fall and you know a lot of folks they are
saying so much has increased over time.
Even my car insurance, right,
I just saw an increase there.
Are we seeing an increase when it
comes to healthcare coverage as well?
Yeah, minimum of 5% usually each year.
I mean like everything else,
like you said, it increases home prices,
food, it's going to increase.
So let's talk about what you
do with people, you know,
how you help them through
this process really they just
give you a call schedule.
Appointment and you go
through all of the options.
We look at everything
and I ask more questions.
They thought I would how
many doctors do you have?
And I keep going. Who else do you see?
And they keep going.
So we want to make sure
everybody's in network,
want to make sure if you have meds,
they're in formulary because one
medication can make a difference.
Yeah. So when people are looking
to pick the correct coverage,
what are some of the things
that they should keep in mind?
Or maybe, Kelly,
some of the things that you come
across that folks aren't thinking
about, it is network.
Especially in Toledo it's can I
get Cleveland Clinic can I get
University of Michigan that's
you know we want to make sure
that we're getting services are
are in network if they're not
they're not going to be paid for
right and then you're looking
at a bill and going I thought
that I was covered you know
so doing on your own if you want
to great more power to you but
for I would say for 95% of the
population we're the resource
where we look everything up for you
you mentioned subsidies earlier for
for folks who. Maybe they have a
spouse or child who's not covered.
Talk a little bit more about subsidies.
What exactly is that in in what's available?
So subsidy is a discount off your
health insurance, unlike your auto
insurance or your homeowners.
That's based off your activity or your
record or health insurance is not.
So everybody pays the same rate
as the other person who is the
same age as them, male or female.
So the plans are higher.
So there's a subsidy or
discount based off income.
It'll give you a better monthly premium.
OK, yeah.
Nice, Kelly. So what are some of
the because open enrollment is
something we we see every year.
There are changes even like we
mentioned we're on deadline for
tomorrow actually to make sure
that we have and yours are not.
What are some of the biggest
changes that we're seeing
mental health on a?
Teledoc basis a couple of carriers
are offering mental health via teledoc
to where you can get regular copays
to see a therapist psychiatrist you
don't have to go into an office broader
networks some carriers are offering
if we're we offer you know insurance
in Columbus or Cleveland you're in
network with your plan in Toledo.
So broader networks is the biggest thing.
Subsidies for families who have
group through maybe a spouse,
but they don't offer any,
you know any payout for their family or kids.
They can get their own plan on a subsidy.
I've seen many people who the rules before
were just killing middle class families.
So we have a lot more options this year.
And then I do want to mention quickly,
Medicare Open enrollment
is going on right now.
So for folks who are 65 and older,
they can be looking into their plans right
now. Right now Medicare Open
enrollment runs through December 7th.
So those people that are on.
Like your advantage or Part D,
this is where they can
change their plan for next
year. OK, cool. Well, Kelly, thanks so much
for all. Thanks for having me.
And your phone number, you know,
people want to give you a call schedule.
That appointment should be on the screen.
I think we did have it up. Here it is.
If you could give Kelly a call
and schedule that appointment.
Sit down, look at your options.
It's the same number.
My mom calls me out.
So they're finally watching today.
So high then.
Yeah. Alright.
Thanks for coming in.
Thank you
so much. Well, when Toledo's longest
running 9:00 AM show continues
from the heart cancer survivors
expressed themselves and put their
talents to the test in an upcoming show.
How you can support them
when good day continues.